<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/tag/web-applications/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2019-10-16T14:44:39+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/tag/web-applications/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Otto SRL | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Multimedia design and full stack development</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">A new django admin experience</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/django-baton" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A new django admin experience" />
      <published>2019-10-16T12:00:00+02:00</published>
      <updated>2019-10-16T12:00:00+02:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/django-baton</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/django-baton">&lt;p&gt;What about a cool, modern and responsive django admin template?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Django is a great framework, it let’s you build complex web applications quickly and reliably. All the front-end stuff is up to the developer, while the back-end can be auto-generated registering your apps to the django admin application. That’s great, because you can focus on how the application will look like, having most of the boring and repetitive backoffice work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The django default admin theme has changed over the years, and at the time of this writing it is almost fully responsive. But we think it’s too minimal, it lacks a convenient sidebar menu and some teaks to make large forms more readable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/django-baton.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;django-baton index page&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here comes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.github.com/otto-torino/django-baton&quot;&gt;django-baton&lt;/a&gt;, a fully responsive django admin theme, based on &lt;strong&gt;Bootstrap 4&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;FontAwesome 5&lt;/strong&gt; (free edition). Lçet’s take a look at its main features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;fully responsive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;custom and flexible sidebar menu (titles, apps, models and free voices supported)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;form tabs out of the box (just set some css classes)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;custom text input filters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;lazy loading and preview of the uploaded images&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;index dashboard with google analytics api&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;easy customizable recompiling the js app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The philosophy behind django-baton is: &lt;strong&gt;overwrite as few django stuff as possible&lt;/strong&gt;.  &lt;br /&gt;
Such philosophy assures a great compatibility among new django releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We developed &lt;strong&gt;django-baton&lt;/strong&gt; for us, and for you. It’s free to use (&lt;strong&gt;MIT License&lt;/strong&gt;), as almost any other project we develop. Try it, and let us know how do you feel about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need help? &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mail@otto.to.it&quot;&gt;Contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We can also create a new brand and custom django-baton version for your project&lt;/strong&gt;, add components and functionality, create new widgets or write the entire backend for you if necessary, &lt;strong&gt;we’re quite good and fast at doing it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>abidibo</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Web Applications" />
      
        <category term="Baton" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">What about a cool, modern and responsive django admin template?</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">We introduce you… Tazebao</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/tazebao" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We introduce you... Tazebao" />
      <published>2019-10-16T11:00:00+02:00</published>
      <updated>2019-10-16T11:00:00+02:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/tazebao</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tazebao">&lt;p&gt;A cool newsletter management web application which focuses on the important things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retain your customers is one of the main goal for your activity, every serious marketing strategy takes into account the problem of customer loyalty. In the era of internet one of the best instruments you may find to keep in touch with your customers, present them your new activities, services and stuff, is to keep a good and selected mailing list, and produce scheduled campaigns which should be at the same time useful and not weraring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Tazebao helps you in doing exactly this. It will give you the instruments to store lists of customers e-mails, group them by any criteria, and produce rich and nice-looking campaigns that can be sent immediately or at any time to the desired groups of customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.github.com/otto-torino/tazebao&quot;&gt;Tazebao&lt;/a&gt; is a django web application developed and manteined by Otto SRL. It’s free to use (MIT License) and you can find all the needed instructions in the github project page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Its main features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;REST service to connect your data to any existing website (collect new e-mails, show yor campaigns, etc…)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;subscribers organized in lists&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;multi-user platform, each user can see and manage only his contents&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;drag and drop functionality provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/voidlabs/mosaico&quot;&gt;mosaico&lt;/a&gt;, with some additions (track links and more template variables)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;scheduling of dispatches&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dispatch report and single e-mail report&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;statistics about openings, link clicking and bounces management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, we know there are many other newsletter services out there, but they become quite expensive when your mailing list grows. Also they offer you a product as is, which fits well for most use cases, but not all. We’ve personally developed this newsletter mangement system, we can help you installing it and modify it to suit your needs. Or we can offer it as a service, running your accounts on our application instances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fell free to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mail@otto.to.it&quot;&gt;contact&lt;/a&gt; us if you need more information or some help with Tazebao!&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>abidibo</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Web Applications" />
      
        <category term="Tazebao" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">A cool newsletter management web application which focuses on the important things.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Cookie Policy Made Easy</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/cookierulez" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cookie Policy Made Easy" />
      <published>2017-07-27T10:00:00+02:00</published>
      <updated>2017-07-27T10:00:00+02:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/cookierulez</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cookierulez">&lt;p&gt;GDPR, Cookie Policy, let us help you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last years the EU has approved new data protection rules which affects the great majority of web sites out there. There are many which didn’t applied to this rules yet, many which cannot sustain the effort, or don’t have the necessary tools and skills to manage all the requiremets. Here comes &lt;a href=&quot;https://cookierulez.sqrt64.it&quot;&gt;Cookierulez&lt;/a&gt;, an open source web application which aims to get your life easier when dealing with webn sites cookie policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/cookierulez.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cookierulez Banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cookierulez&lt;/strong&gt; does a good job in automating the collection, description and management of installed cookies. Its main features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;multi-user platform: each user can manage his web sites and provide all the information that couldn’t be collected automatically&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cookies are categorized&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cookies have a description and many other info that shoul be displayed to the user&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dark and light themes out of the box&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;custom consent to different cookies categories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-it-works&quot;&gt;How it works&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s super easy to use Cookierulez:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Register a web site&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wait for the application to scrape all the urls in depth (you can choose how deep should be the scraping), or launch it manually&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wait the application to analyze all the scraped urls to get the installed cookies, or launch it manually&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cookierulez will automatically divide cookies into categories and provide descriptions basing upon an always growing dictionary&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make some manual modifications if you need them&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Include a script and a stylesheet in your website to power on the cookie banner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;third-parties-cookies&quot;&gt;Third parties cookies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cookierulez does a great job blocking third party cookies when the user disables them. Thir party cookies are the ones installed bu other external scripts, embeds or widgets like analytics, youtube, vimeo, sharethis, etc…
Cookierulez provides a way to block such external resources until the user confirm his consent, you just need to set some attributes on the html elemnts and let Cookierulez do its job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interested&quot;&gt;Interested?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to know more about Cookierulez, or use it to forget about cookies, then just &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mail@otto.to.it&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt; we’ll help you setting up a proper solution.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>abidibo</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Web Applications" />
      
        <category term="Cookierulez" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">GDPR, Cookie Policy, let us help you!</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
