<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/tag/tazebao/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2019-12-05T09:53:46+00:00</updated>
  <id>/tag/tazebao/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Otto SRL | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Multimedia design and full stack development</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Tazebao’s got a new face</title>
      <link href="/tazebao-new-face" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tazebao's got a new face" />
      <published>2019-12-05T09:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-12-05T09:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/tazebao-new-face</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/tazebao-new-face">&lt;p&gt;We introduce you the new Tazebao application!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A shining react &lt;strong&gt;powered app&lt;/strong&gt;, which consumes Tazebao’s REST API in order to assure a great experience to our users.
The new app has all the features of the previous (and still working) web app, with the addition of some stats like the unsubscription rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mosaico template generator is now fully integrated inside the app, and the workflow needed to compose a campaign is straigthforward, because the concept of template is now managed under the scenes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/tazebao-new-mosaico.png&quot; alt=&quot;Choose lists&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After creating the e-mail contents, you can send your campaign: choose your lists and send immediately or schedule a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/tazebao-new-send.png&quot; alt=&quot;Choose lists&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/tazebao-new-send2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Send&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A campaign can be dispatched multiple times and for every dispatch the application provides full statistics: open rate and events, click rate and events, bounces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/tazebao-new-campaign-view.png&quot; alt=&quot;Send&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We added the &lt;strong&gt;duplicate&lt;/strong&gt; campaign feature, so that you can compose a new e-mail starting from one of the previus&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/tazebao-new-campaign-tools.png&quot; alt=&quot;Send&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new application was designed in order to provide a simplified workflow for the user, and it succeed in this task, but at the same time retains all the features the old application had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mail@otto.to.it&quot;&gt;contact&lt;/a&gt; us if you need more information or some help with Tazebao!&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>S. Contini</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Web Applications" />
      
        <category term="Tazebao" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">We introduce you the new Tazebao application!</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">We introduce you… Tazebao</title>
      <link href="/tazebao" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We introduce you... Tazebao" />
      <published>2019-10-16T09:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-10-16T09:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/tazebao</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/tazebao">&lt;p&gt;A cool newsletter management web application which focuses on the important things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retain your customers is one of the main goal for your activity, every serious marketing strategy takes into account the problem of customer loyalty. In the era of internet one of the best instruments you may find to keep in touch with your customers, present them your new activities, services and stuff, is to keep a good and selected mailing list, and produce scheduled campaigns which should be at the same time useful and not wearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Tazebao helps you in doing exactly this. It will give you the instruments to store lists of customers e-mails, group them by any criteria, and produce rich and nice-looking campaigns that can be scheduled or sent immediately to the desired groups of recipients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.github.com/otto-torino/tazebao&quot;&gt;Tazebao&lt;/a&gt; is a django web application developed and manteined by Otto SRL. It’s free to use (MIT License) and you can find all the needed instructions in the github project page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at its main features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rest-web-service&quot;&gt;REST web service&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tazebao includes a REST web service in order to connect your data to any existing website (collect new e-mails, show yor campaigns, etc…). This is great because you can design your subscription form as you like, and then consume Tazebao’s API to make it work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/tazebao-rest.png&quot; alt=&quot;Subscription form&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;subscriber-organized-in-lists&quot;&gt;Subscriber organized in lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manage you lists of subscribers, send targeted campaigns by dividing your customers in group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;multi-user-platform&quot;&gt;Multi-user platform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tazebao is a multi-user platform, can manage an indefinite number of clients, each with its credentials. Every user can see and manage only his contents. You can give full access to the platform being sure that no one can interfeer with others’ campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;templates-with-dragdrop-functionality&quot;&gt;Templates with drag&amp;amp;drop functionality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tazebao integrates &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/voidlabs/mosaico&quot;&gt;Mosaico&lt;/a&gt; as e-mail template engine, in order to keep the editorial task as simple as possible. Drag and drop some blocks, change texts and add images, and you’ll end up with a perfect looking e-mail looking nice on every device. Moreover we added some functionality to the default Mosaico engine in order to add tracking links capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/tazebao-mosaico.png&quot; alt=&quot;Subscription form&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;scheduling-of-dispatches&quot;&gt;Scheduling of dispatches&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need to send a campaign that day at that hour you can. Just set your campaign dispatch time and Tazebao will do the rest. Tazebao constantly checks if some campaigns are scheduled, and it will promptly send them at the right time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/tazebao-scheduling.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Scheduling&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;statistics-and-reports&quot;&gt;Statistics and reports&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tazebao provides reports about campaigns and single e-mails dispatches. &lt;br /&gt;
Something got wrong? Tazebao will tell you what. You can see bounced e-mails and the reason behind the event, giving you the possibility to clean your mailing list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tazebao provides you statistics about opening rates and link clicks, see who clicked which link and when!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/tazebao-stats.png&quot; alt=&quot;Scheduling&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, we know there are many other newsletter services out there, but they become quite expensive when your mailing list grows. Also they offer you a product as is, which fits well for most use cases, but not all. We’ve personally developed this newsletter mangement system, &lt;strong&gt;we can help you installing it and modify it to suit your needs. Or we can offer it as a service, running your accounts on our application instances.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mail@otto.to.it&quot;&gt;contact&lt;/a&gt; us if you need more information or some help with Tazebao!&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>S. Contini</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Web Applications" />
      
        <category term="Tazebao" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">A cool newsletter management web application which focuses on the important things.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
